Guide to Emeric Deutsch Collection RG.060
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Emeric Deutsch Collection
1998-2023
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.060
9 Linear Feet 18 manuscript boxes
Good
Biographical / Historical
Emeric Deutsch recieved his MS in mathematics in 1967 and PhD in mathematics in 1969 from the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. He was a professor at the institution starting the 1970-1971 school semseter in the Mathematics Department.
Content Description
The Emeric Deutsch Collection contains documents from 1998 to 2023. These documents were assembled by Deutsch throughout his career at the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn as a Mathematics professor. There are published works, graphs of formulas, research materials, notes and correspondence. The collection is 9 linear feet, located on bay 25, shelves 4A, 5A and 6A of the Poly Archives.
Arrangement
This collection comprises 18 manuscript boxes. Original order was maintained when possible. However, during the accessioning process, some contents were merged together and arranged into these six series: Series I: Scholarly Reference Materials and Notes, 2001-2023 Series II: Publications by Emeric Deutsch, 2018-2022 Series III: Graphs, 2010-2023 Series IV: Correspondence, 1998-2021 Series V: Notes, undated, Series VI: 2024 Accretion
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Material was donated by Yvonne Deutsch in 2023. The accession number associated with this collection is 2023-007.
mathematics
- Series I: Scholarly Reference Materials and Notes, 2001-2023
  - Research Articles I, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research Articles II, 2022 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Research Articles III, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Research Articles IV, 2019-2022 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Research Articles V, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Research Articles VI, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Research Articles VII, 2021-2022 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Research Articles VIII, 2022 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Research Articles IX, 2022 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Research Articles X, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Research Articles XI, 2017-2019 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Research Articles and Notes XII, 2019 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Composition Research Articles XIII, 2014-2016 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Crystal Cubic Carbon Research Articles XIV, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fibonacci Research Articles XV, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fibonacci Research Articles XVI, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Research Articles XVII, 2021 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Research Articles XVIII, 2022 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Research Articles XIX, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Research Articles XX, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Research Articles XXI, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Research Articles XXII, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Research Articles XXIII, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Research Articles XXIV, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Research Articles XXV, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Research Articles XXVI, 2012-2022 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Research Articles XXVII, 2022 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Research Articles XXVIII, 2020-2023 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Research Articles XXIX, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Research Articles XXX, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - (Nanostar) Dendrimer Research Articles XXXI, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Deutsch path Research Articles XXXII, 2018-2021 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Catalan Addendum Research Articles and Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dyck Paths Research Notes XXXIV, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Production Matrix Research Articles XXXV, 2020-2021 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Polymer Research Articles and Notes XXXVI, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - OEIS Reference Materials XXXVII, 2021 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - OEIS Reference Materials XXXVIII, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - OEIS Reference Materials and Graph Notes XXXIX, 2021 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Deutsch Paths Papers by Helmut Prediger in Journals XL, 2020-2021 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Permutations OEIS Reference Materials XLI, May-August 2010 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Oxide Networks Reference Materials XLII (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Catalan Addendum Research Articles and Notes XLIII (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Permutations Blocks, Transportation Distance XLIV (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - OEIS Reference Materials and Research Papers XLV, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Research Articles XLVI, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Research Articles XLVII, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Research Articles XLVIII, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Series II: Publications by Emeric Deutsch, 2018-2022
  - Publications of Emeric Deutsch and Paper Reviews I, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Emeric Deutsch Co-Publications with Sergi Elizalde II, 2018-2020 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Emeric Deutsch Co-Publications with Sandi Klavzar III, 2020-2022 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Publications by Deutsch, Klavzar, and Romih IV, 2018-2022 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series III: Graphs, 2010-2023
  - Permutation Blocks Graphs I, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Graph II, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Graph III, August 1, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Topological Indices Graphs IV, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - M-Poly Theory Graphs V, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Paths and Structures Graphs VI, December 31, 2020 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Optimal Cost Networks #1 Graph VII, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Optimal Cost Networks #3 Graph VIII, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Optimal Cost Networks #4 Graph IX, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Compositions Graphs and OEIS Reference Materials X, 2018-2021 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Triangular Chain Graphs XI, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - SOWMYA and Hexagon Graphs XII, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Polygon Graphs XIII, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Octogon Graphs XIV, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Polygon Graphs XV, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hexagon/Polygon Graphs XVI, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Polygon Graphs XVII, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Polygon Graphs XVIII, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Polygon Graphs IXX, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Graphs XX, 2017-2019 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chain and System Graphs XXI, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Degrees of Asymmetry (Compositions, Partitions, Barographs) XXII, 2020 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Binary Words XXIII, 2018-2020 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXIV, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXV, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXVI (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs with Research Articles XXVII, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXVIII, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bismuth Tri-Iodide Chain and Sheet with Article XXIX, 2020 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hexagon XXX, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Sergi Bijection Graphs and Notes XXXI, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Sergi Graphs XXXII, undated (Box 9, Box 5)
  - Wiener Graph and OEIS XXXIII, 2017-2018 (Box 9, Box 6)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXXIV, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXXV, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXXVI, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - M-Polynomial Graphs XXXVII, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - M-Polynomial XXXVIII, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Do Do Do ("Do But Check") XXXIX, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Graphs with Notes XL, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Unfinished Graphs XLI, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Graphs XLII, 2012-2022 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Circular Generalized Phenylene XLIII, 2018-2021 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Network and Circular Graphs XLIV, 2021 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Honeycomb Networks and Brincidofovir XLV, 2023 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Graphs XLVI, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Permutations Blocks #Double Block-Descents XLVII, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Permutations Graphs (# Isolated FP, #Pairs of Adjacent FP) XLVIII, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Permutations (Block-related statistics) XLIX, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Graphs w/ Articles L, 2021-2022 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Optimal Cost Networks LI, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hyaluronic Acid Conjugates LII, 2022 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Permutation Block #block-ascents LIII, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Permutation Blocks LIV, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Permutation Block #blocks of length LV, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Permutation Blocks LVI, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Graphs LVII, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Graphs with Notes and Correspondences LVIII, 2016-2021 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Fibonacci Cubes LIX, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Fibonacci like Cubes LX, 2019 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fibonacci Cubes LXI, 2014 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Fibonacci and Lucas Cubes LXII, 2014-2019 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Matchable Lucas Cubes LXIII, 2019 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Fibonacci Cubes LXIX, 2019 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Fibonacci Cubes - Eccentricity LXX, 2017 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Dyck Paths, Height of First Valley "HEFIVA" LXXI, 2014-2016 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Lucas Cubes LXXII, 2019 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Permutations Blocks LXXIII, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Lucas Cubes LXXIV, 2014-2019 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bijection Dyck Paths LXXV, 2003-2021 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Secondary Structures LXXVI, 2020 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Elementary Math LXXVII, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Conjugation LXXVIII, 2020-2021 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Analysis of CCC p-gons - Viabin Conjugate LXXIX, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - CL Deu LXXX, 2021 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Heinz Partition LXXXI, 2016 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Viabin LXXXII, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Viabin and Heinz LXXXIII, 2016 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - D&K #2 M-Polynomial Theory LXXXIV, 2014 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Partition Data LXXXV, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Heinz Vabin LXXXVI, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - CCCK (n) LXXXVII, 2017-2020 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - CCCS (n) LXXXVIII, 2018 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Permutation, Vabin-Heinz, Partition Graphs LXXXIX, 2015-2018 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Viabin Conjugate XC, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Partition Conjugate Max-Min XCI, August 31, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Heinz Number XCII, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Viabin XCIII, 2017 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Permutation Blocks, Strong Fixed Blocks XCIV, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Permutations (Small Ascents-Block Related) XCVI (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Permutations Fixed Blocks XCVIII, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Permutation Blocks XCIX, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Permutation Block-Inversion Number C, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Permutation Block-Peaks XCIX, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Permutation Maximum Block Length, Minimum Block Length CII, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Permutation #Blocks of Length CI, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Permutations Sum of Block-Headers CIV, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Permutation # Block LRM CIII, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Permutations Blocks Mish-Mash CIV, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Permutation Blocks, # of Odd Blocks (Odd Size), # of Even Blocks (Even Size) CV, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Permutation Blocks #Block Starting with an Odd/Even Number CVI, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - DEU 1-Piece Closed CVII, 2021 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - DEU Path CX, 2021 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - DEU Statistics CXI, 2021 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Chain, Grid, Rhombus Oxide CXII, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Amylose CXIII, 2021 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Spiral Benzenoid Graphs with Correspondence, Notes, and Article CXI, 2020-2021 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Starphene Graphs and Articles CXV, 2013-2022 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Fan, Helm and Chain Networks CXIV, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Benes Network CXV, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Do! Graphs CXIX, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Bethe Cactus Latice Graphs D.C.E CXX, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Topological Indices, Flower CXXI, 2022 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Binary Words with no 00's CXXII, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Blue Starch Iodine CXXIII, Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Amylose CXXIV, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Graphs CXXV, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Graphs CXXVI, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Graphs CXXVII, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Graphs CXXVIII, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Graphs CXXIX, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Graphs CXXX, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Graphs CXXXI, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Graphs CXXXII, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Graphs CXXXIII, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Graphs CXXXIV, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Graphs CXXXV, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Graphs CXXXVI, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Graphs CXXXVII, July 26, 2021 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Graphs CXXXVIII, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Graphs CXXIX, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Graphs CXL, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Graphs CXLI, Undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Graphs CXLII, Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Graphs CXLIII, Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Graphs CXLIV, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Correspondence, 1998-2021
  - About Publications I, 1998-2001 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Andrews, George II, 2017 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Elizalde, Sergi III, 2010-2020 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Elizalde, Sergi ("Our Bijection") IV, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Fibonacci and Lucas Cubes V, 2014-2019 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Klavzar, Sandi VI, 2014-2021 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Prodinger, Helmut VII, 2020-2021 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Stanley, Richard VIII, 2003-2011 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence IX, 2018-2020 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Series V: Notes, undated
  - Permutation Blocks I, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Permutation Blocks II, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Blue Starch-Iodine III, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Permutation Block-Related IV (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Permutations Notecards V (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Permutations Notecards VI (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Permutations Notecards VII (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Permutations Notecards VIII (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Permutations Notecards VIX (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Permutations Notecards X (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Series VI: 2024 Accretion
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 2017-2022 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Subseries B: Graph Sheets of Equations
    - Fibonacci Cube Irregularity, April 12, 2019 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - The Symbolic Method (to Paul D. Hanna), undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Secondary Structure, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Fib Cubes Irregularity Conjecture, February 20, 2019 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Notebooks (Labeled)
    - "!!!!" (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Auxi", "Skew Duck Paths", "Hex Trees" (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Compo" (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Crowns (Coronenes) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Derivations (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Dyck (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Matula (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Misc Derivations (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - RNA (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - RNA 2 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "S" (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "Sandi", "D+K 2", "My Poly" (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Vella (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Wiener Polynomial (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Subseries D: Notebooks (Unlabeled) (Box 21, Item 5-8)
  - Subseries E: Photograph of Emeric Deutsch with unidentified colleagues, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Subseries F: Writings by Emeric Deutsch
    - Norms and Eigenvalues of Metrics Thesis, June 1967 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Vectorial and Matricial Norms Dissertation, June 1969 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Problems Proposals, 2001-2016 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Co-author with Others, 1978-2010 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Co-author with Others, 2012-2022 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Co-author with Sergi Elizalde, 2003-2021 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Journal Reprints by Emeric Deutsch, 1956-2001 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Publications List (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Writings by Emeric Deutsch, 2004-2012 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Subseries G: Writings by Others
    - The American Mathematical Monthly, 2016 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - OEIS Reference Materials (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - The Practical Treatment of Integral Equations by H. Buckner, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Reprint Articles by Others (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - West University of Timișoara Bulevardul V. Pârvan nr. 4, (1949) 1962-1970 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - West University of Timișoara Documentary Library Books, 1998-2006 (Box 24, Folder 2)